kontera.com 2014-06-25

# About Us | Privacy Policy | Kontera

## Kontera Privacy Notice

Welcome to the Kontera Technologies, Inc. ("Kontera") web site at [http://www.kontera.com/ (the "Site")](http://www.kontera.com/).

Kontera operates a technology platform (the “Platform”) that provides marketing insights and digital advertising solutions to the world’s leading brands and marketing agencies.

Kontera values the privacy of Internet visitors (“Users”) to the Site, our Customers, and Users that visit websites where our analytics and digital advertising technology (our “Technology”) is enabled. For purposes of this policy, we refer to our Platform and Technology as the “Services.”

This Privacy Notice describes what information we gather from Users of the Site and our Customers, how we use that information, and what we do to protect it. This Privacy Notice also describes the privacy practices pertaining to our Services, how the Technology gathers information from Users, how it uses that information, and what we do to protect the information stored on our Platform. This Privacy Notice is incorporated into the Kontera Terms of Service. Your use of the Site and any personal information you provide on the Site are subject to the terms of this Privacy Notice and Kontera's Terms of Service.

### Advertising Choices

Kontera specializes in providing consumers with information that is related to what they are reading. We get our revenues by showing editorially relevant ads to consumers.

When choosing which ads to show you, Kontera does not use any information that personally identifies you, such as your name, address, e-mail, phone number, etc.

While Kontera most often shows you ads based on the content of the page you are visiting, we occasionally show some ads based on additional non personally identifiable information, such as the types of websites you visit, the ads you view, interactions you've had with ads, and searches you conduct on other websites.

We take reasonable steps to not collect or pass to 3rd parties pages and data regarding medical conditions; certain aspects of personal life or financial situations; gambling; alcoholic beverages; violence, or "adult" products or services.

We identify users by simply recognizing tokens (cookies) stored in users' browsers by us or one of our partners. With this information, we may show ads related to the interests associated with those cookies. Kontera's advertising products collects this information only from websites on which our advertising products are enabled.

Additionally, we may engage with certain 3rd parties that provide additional information on demographics, geography, and interest areas that we may leverage in selecting ads to display to consumers.

Although we may share our data with 3rd party service providers to deliver Kontera advertising campaigns, we do not authorize any of these partiers to resell or further share this data. These 3rd parties work on our behalf only to support the delivery of our advertising campaigns. When we work with them, we will provide the data specified above. From time to time we may turn off the collection of any data.  

If you prefer that Kontera not collect any information about your website visits for the purpose of delivering targeted advertising, you may opt out by [clicking here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

We may also work with partners that are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) and work with industry-leading companies committed to building consumer awareness and establishing responsible business and data management practices and standards in online advertising. [Click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) to learn more about the NAI. To opt-out of targeting by other member companies, please [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

When you opt out, an opt-out cookie will be placed onto your computer. The opt-out cookie tells Kontera not to use any of your information for delivering relevant online advertisements. Please note that if you block cookies, the opt-out process may not function properly. Please also note that if you delete, block, or otherwise restrict cookies, or if you use a different computer or Internet browser, you will need to set your opt-out choice again for that computer or browser.

##   
Privacy Practices for the Kontera Customers and Site Visitors

### What We Collect

**Information You Provide:**  
When you visit our Site, we may ask you to provide information such as your name, title, company name, email address, and telephone number.If you sign up to use our Services we may ask to provide information such as your name, address, email address, telephone number, Social Security Number, and Tax Identification Number.

**Information We Automatically Collect When You Visit Our Site:**  
When you visit our Site, we may automatically record certain information from your device, including your IP address or other device address or ID, web browser and/or device type, the web pages or sites that you visit just before or just after you use the Sites, the pages or other content you view or otherwise interact with on our Sites, and the dates and times that you visit, access, or use our Sites.

We collect certain information through the use of “cookies” and other tracking technologies to better understand how our visitors navigate through the Site, learn what content is being reviewed, and administer the Site. Cookies are small text files that Web servers place on an Internet user’s computer that are designed to store basic information and to recognize your browser. We may use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A session cookie disappears after you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Service. Please review your web browser “Help" file to learn the proper way to modify your cookie settings. Please note that if you delete, or choose not to accept, cookies from the Service, you may not be able to utilize the features of the Service to their fullest potential.

We work with third party partners, such as Google Analytics, that may use cookies and other tracking technologies to collect information about your online activities over time and across different web sites when you visit our Sites. For example, we may share your information with analytics providers who help us understand how visitors use our web site. 

## How We Use and Share Your Information

**How We Use Your Information:  **  
We may use your information to provide our Services to you, for payment and billing purposes, and to communicate with you.  

**When Kontera Discloses Information:**  
Kontera does not share personal information collected via the Site or other information collected from Customers with other organizations for their marketing or promotional uses without your express consent.

Kontera works with some authorized service providers to provide website hosting and maintenance as well as other services for us. Kontera requires these services providers to safeguard personal information you provide to us. To the extent it is necessary for these service providers to complete their contractual obligations to Kontera, these third parties may have access to or process your personal information. Kontera generally limits their use of your personal information to the purpose for which it was shared.

Kontera may also disclose information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with state and federal laws (such as U.S. Copyright law) or respond to a court order, judicial or other government subpoena, or warrant. In some cases, we may make such disclosures without first providing notice to Users.

Kontera also reserves the right to disclose information that we believe, in good faith, is appropriate or necessary to take precautions against liability; protect Kontera from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses; to investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations; to assist government enforcement agencies; to protect the security or integrity of the Site; or to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Kontera, our Users, or others. And in the event that Kontera is acquired by or merged with a third-party entity, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information that we have collected from Users as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control.

**Updating / Deleting your Personal Information:**  
If you’d like to update, correct, delete, or deactivate any personal information that you have provided via this Site, please send your request to [support@kontera.com](mailto:support@kontera.com), and we will process your request.

##   
Privacy Practices for the Kontera Services

### Overview of Our Services:  
Kontera provides a Technology that places in-text advertising onto our network of publishers’ websites across the web. We also have a Platform that helps us understand whether Users interact with our Technology and how they interact with the Technology. We provide both our advertiser and publisher clients with access to the Platform so they can understand User interactions with our Technology as well.

### What Information We Collect and How We Use It

**"Cookies" Information:  **  
Kontera uses cookies and web beacons in connection with our Technology.

**"Automatically Collected" Information:  **  
Kontera automatically collects certain non-personally identifiable information from your web browser in connection with our Technology and stores this information on our Platform. This information may include Internet Protocol address, web browser type, the URL of the web pages or sites you visit where our Technology is enabled, the date/time you visit those web pages or sites, the URL of the web page you were on prior to visiting the web page where our Technology is enabled, and searches you conduct on websites where our Technology is enabled.

**Website Content:**  
Kontera may collect the content of the websites you visit or link to on social media.

**Information Collected From Social Media Services:**  
Kontera may collect information, including personal information, from social media services that you use. For example, we collect information such as your name, social media handle, postings or other actions you take, and connections.  However, please remember that the manner in which social media services use, store and disclose your information is governed by the policies of such third parties, and Company shall have no liability or responsibility for the privacy practices or other actions of any social media services.

**How We Use Information We Collect Through Our Services:**  
Kontera uses the information that we collect via our Technology to provide and improve our Services, to understand and analyze the way our Users interact with our Technology, to serve more relevant advertising, and for ad delivery and reporting purposes.

**Your Advertising Choices (Opt-out Rights):**  
We use the non-personally identifiable information we collect to deliver targeted advertising on many other websites you may visit. In order to collect and use this information, we work with vendors who are part of the Network Advertising Initiative, a cooperative of online marketing and analytics companies committed to building consumer awareness and establishing responsible business and data management practices and standards. If you prefer that Kontera does not collect non-personally identifiable information about your website visits for the purpose of delivering targeted advertising, you may opt out by visiting the NAI website by [clicking here.](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)  When you opt out, an opt-out cookie will be placed onto your computer. The opt-out cookie tells our vendors not to use your information for delivering relevant online advertisements. Please note that if you block cookies, the opt-out process may not function properly. Please also note that if you delete, block, or otherwise restrict cookies, or if you use a different computer or Internet browser, you will need to renew your opt-out choice. 

**Do Not Track:**  
Because an industry-standard Do Not Track protocol has not yet been established, we do not currently respond to Do Not Track signals.

## How We Share the Information We Collect

### When Kontera Discloses Information:  
Kontera discloses Automatically Collected and other aggregate non-personally-identifiable information with interested third parties to assist such parties in understanding the usage, viewing, and demographic patterns for certain programs, content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality on the web site.

Kontera works with some authorized service providers to provide website hosting and maintenance as well as other services for us. Kontera requires these services providers to safeguard personal information you provide to us. To the extent it is necessary for these service providers to complete their contractual obligations to Kontera, these third parties may have access to or process your personal information. Kontera generally limits their use of your personal information to the purpose for which it was shared.

Kontera may also disclose information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with state and federal laws (such as U.S. Copyright law) or respond to a court order, judicial or other government subpoena, or warrant. In some cases, we may make such disclosures without first providing notice to Users.

Kontera also reserves the right to disclose information that we believe, in good faith, is appropriate or necessary to take precautions against liability; protect Kontera from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses; to investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations; to assist government enforcement agencies; to protect the security or integrity of the Site; or to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Kontera, our Users, or others. And in the event that Kontera is acquired by or merged with a third-party entity, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information that we have collected from Users as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control.

## Privacy Practices for the Kontera Customers, Site, and Services

**Children's Privacy:**  
Kontera’s Site, products and services are designed for those 13 years of age and older. Kontera does not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 13. If we are made aware that we have received personal information from someone under 13, we will use reasonable efforts to remove that information from our records.

**Data Security and Data Retention:**  
Kontera uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security all information under our control. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the 100% security of any information you transmit to Kontera, and you do so at your own risk. We make commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards

We retain the information Automatically Collected by our Technology for up to 18 months at which time it may be aggregated and stored for up to five years. We retain information collected from social media services for up for six months.

**Changes and Updates to this Privacy Notice:**  
This Privacy Notice may be revised periodically without further notice to you and this will be reflected by the effective date below. Please revisit this page to stay aware of any changes. In general, we only use your personal information in the manner described in the Privacy Notice in effect when we received that personal information. Your continued use of the Site constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Notice and any future revisions.

**Effective Date:**  
This Privacy Notice is effective as of June 24, 2014.

**Kontera Contact Information:**  
Please contact Kontera with any questions or comments about this Privacy Notice, your personal information, our third-party disclosure practices, or your consent choices at: 1940 Bryant St. San Francisco, California 94110, U.S.A. and email: [support@kontera.com](mailto:support@kontera.com).
